http://www.chapinmfg.com/policies/privacy-policy

Search
Sale
Sprayers
By Usage:
Turf & Agriculture
By Type:
Spreaders
By Usage:
Snow & Ice
By Type:
Troubleshooting & Videos
F.A.Q.
Troubleshooting & Videos
F.A.Q.
Privacy Policy
This privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) governs the manner in which Chapin International, Inc. and its affiliates including without limitation Chapin Outfitters, LLC, Heath Outdoor Products, Inc. and Chapin Custom Molding, Inc. (collectively, “Chapin”) collects, uses, maintains and discloses information collected from you and related to you, with the use of any of the Chapin company websites, including, without limitation, chapinmfg.com, chapinportal.com, hydrofeed.com, chapincustommolding.com, heathmfg.com, https://chapinaustralia.com.au/, and mixesonexit.com (collectively, the “Websites”). This Privacy Policy applies to the Websites and all products and services offered by Chapin. Your use of the Websites constitutes your agreement to the terms, conditions and notices herein. If you do not want to agree to this Privacy Policy, you must not access or use the Websites.
Personal information
Personal information for the purposes of this Privacy Policy means information that can be used to personally identify you or is associated with any such information, or personal information may be defined by the laws of the location where you live. Chapin may collect personal information from you in a variety of ways, including, but not limited to, when you visit the Websites, register an account on the Websites, place an order, subscribe to a newsletter, respond to a survey, fill out a form, and in connection with other activities, services, features, or resources that Chapin makes available on the Websites. You may be asked for, as appropriate, your name, email address, mailing address, phone number, and/or credit card information when purchasing Chapin products or using Chapin services. You may, however, visit the Websites anonymously. Chapin will collect personal information from you only if you voluntarily submit such information to Chapin. You can always refuse to supply personal information, except that it may prevent them from engaging in certain Website related activities.
Notwithstanding the above, Chapin maintains log files tracking IP addresses to analyze trends, help diagnose problems with Chapin servers, and to monitor traffic/usage in order to provide better service to Website users and visitors. IP addresses are not used by Chapin to personally identify individuals, and Chapin does not link IP addresses to other forms of identifiable information, however IP addresses may be considered to be personal information under the laws of certain jurisdictions.
Non-personal information
Chapin may collect non-personal information about you whenever you interact with the Websites. Non-personal information may include your browser name, the type of computer you use and other technical information about your means of connection to the Websites, such as your operating system, the Internet service providers utilized, and other similar information.
Web browser cookies
The Websites may use "cookies" to enhance your experience. Your web browser places cookies on your hard drive for record-keeping purposes and sometimes to track information about you. Usage of a cookie is not linked to any personal information by Chapin. You may choose to set your web browser to refuse cookies, or to alert you when cookies are being sent. If you do so, note that some parts of the Websites may not function properly.
Some Chapin business partners (e.g., tracking utility companies) may use cookies on the Websites. Chapin does not have access or control over these cookies. For example, the Websites utilize Google Analytics, a common website analytics tool. For more information about Google Analytics, please refer to the website, “How Google uses data when you use our partners’ sites or apps” at http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/.
The Websites use the following categories of cookies:
Strictly necessary cookies - these are cookies that are required for the operation of the Websites
Analytics and customization cookies - these functional cookies collect information that is used either in aggregate form to help Chapin understand how the Websites are being used, how effective marketing campaigns are, or to help Chapin customize the Websites and applications for you in order to enhance your experience.
Performance and functionality cookies - these cookies are used to enhance the performance and functionality of the Websites but are non-essential to their However, without these cookies, certain functionality may become unavailable.
How Chapin uses collected information
Chapin collects and uses personal information for the following purposes:
To personalize the user experience
To understand how Chapin Website users (may use de-identified information in the aggregate) as a group use the services and resources provided on the Websites
To improve the Websites based on the information and feedback Chapin receives from you, the user
To improve customer service
To  help Chapin to more effectively respond to your customer service requests and support
To process transactions and send you email updates about your online order
To provide service when you are placing an order. Chapin does not share this information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to provide the service requested. For example, order tracking information, PayPal or Google Pay, or credit card refunds.
To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other Website feature
To send you information about Chapin  because you opted in to our mailing list. This may include company news, updates, related product or service information, etc. If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, Chapin includes detailed unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email.
How Chapin protects your information
Chapin will make reasonable efforts to ensure that your personal data is properly secured, however, no Website is 100% safe from hackers. If a security breach causes an unauthorized intrusion into Chapin’s systems that materially affects you, then Chapin will promptly notify you in accordance with applicable legal requirements.
Sharing your personal information
Chapin does not sell, trade, or rent personal information to others.
Chapin may share generic aggregated demographic information not linked to any personal information regarding visitors and users with Chapin business partners, trusted affiliates, and advertisers for the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy. Chapin may use third party service providers to help operate its business and the Websites or administer activities on its behalf, such as sending out newsletters or surveys. Chapin may share your information with these third parties for those limited purposes.
Except as part of the sale of all or substantially all of Chapin’s assets, Chapin will not sell, trade, or rent your personal information to any third party unless Chapin has your consent to do so or as otherwise disclosed in this Privacy Policy.
Except where Chapin is required by law to disclose personal information, Chapin will use reasonable efforts to require any person to whom Chapin provides your personal information to comply with our then current Privacy Policy. However, to the extent allowed under applicable law, Chapin will have no liability to you if any person fails to do so.
To be able to serve you, your personal information may be collected, stored and/or processed or otherwise used by or on our behalf both inside and outside the United States by third party service providers, to perform cloud storage, payment processing and other service-related functions on Chapin’s behalf. As a result, that country's courts, governments or law enforcement agencies could obtain disclosure of such information under that country's laws.
Online tracking / Do Not Track
Chapin does not track Website visitors across third party websites to provide targeted advertising and therefore the Websites do not respond to Do Not Track (“DNT”) signals. However, some third party sites do keep track of your browsing activities when they serve you content, which enables them to tailor what they present to you. If you are visiting such sites, your internet browser may allow you to set the DNT signal on your browser so that third parties (particularly advertisers) know you do not want to be tracked.
No collection of children’s personal information
The Websites are intended for audiences at least 18 years old. Chapin does not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. Chapin reserves the right to delete any information believed to be in violation of this Privacy Policy.
Individual Choice and Access
Chapin works to keep your data accurate and up to date, to the extent that you provide us with the information needed to do that. If your data changes (like a new email address), then you’re responsible for notifying Chapin of those changes.
Chapin will retain your information for as long as your Website account is active or as long as needed to provide you services. Chapin may also retain and use your information in order to comply with legal obligations, resolve disputes, prevent fraud and abuse, and enforce agreements.
Chapin will provide an individual access to any personal information held about them within 30 days of any request for that information. Individuals may request this information from Chapin by using the contact information provided herein. Unless it’s prohibited by law, Chapin will remove any personal information about an individual from its servers at their request. There is no charge for an individual to access or update his or her personal information.
Third party websites
You may find advertising or other content on the Websites that link to the sites and services of Chapin partners, suppliers, advertisers, sponsors, licensors and other third parties. Chapin does not control the content or links that appear on these sites and is not responsible for the practices employed by third party websites linked to or from the Websites. In addition, these sites or services, including their content and links, may be constantly changing. These sites and services may have their own privacy policies and customer service policies. Browsing and interaction on any other website, including websites which have a link to the Websites, is subject to that website's own terms and policies.
Social media platforms
The Websites may include social media features, such as links to the Chapin Facebook®, LinkedIn®, or YouTube® pages. These features may collect information about your IP address and which page you’re visiting on the Websites, and they may set a cookie to make sure the feature functions properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on the Websites. Chapin also maintains a presence on social media platforms like Facebook, LinkedIn, and YouTube. Any information, communications, or materials you submit to Chapin via a social media platform is done at your own risk without any expectation of privacy. Chapin cannot control the actions of other users of these platforms or the actions of the platforms themselves. Your interactions with those features and platforms are governed by the privacy policies of the companies that provide them.
No Liability
You understand that electronic communications may be accessed by unauthorized parties when communicated across the Internet, network communications facilities, or other electronic means. You agree that Chapin is not responsible for any electronic communication and/or any of your data which may be lost, altered, intercepted, or stored without authorization during the transmission of any data whatsoever across networks not owned and/or operated by Chapin. Chapin does not guarantee that your information will not be misused or disclosed to third parties. Chapin will not have any liability to you for any such misuse or disclosure.
Changes to this privacy policy
Chapin has the discretion to update this Privacy Policy at any time. When Chapin does update this Privacy Policy, Chapin will revise the updated date at the bottom of this page. Chapin encourages you to frequently check this page for any changes to stay informed about how Chapin is utilizing the personal information it collects. You acknowledge and agree that it is your responsibility to review this Privacy Policy periodically and become aware of modifications.
Your acceptance of these terms
By using the Websites, you signify your acceptance of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Websites. Your continued use of the Websites following the posting of changes to this Privacy Policy will be deemed your acceptance of those changes.
Contacting us
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of the Websites, or your dealings with the Websites, please contact Chapin at:
Chapin International, Inc.
